# NATHAN W MACLAURIN

# Portfolio (11)



GitHub 🔯

# <u>LinkedIn</u>

EMAIL 🖂

# FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## **Summary**

A Lifelong learner transitioning from 2+ years in Software QA and 6+ years in IT with passion for sensible design and dynamic technologies. An adaptable empath who facilitates teamwork with mindful communication and values creative problem-solving.

#### Skills

#### Languages:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, C++

#### **Libraries & Frameworks:**

React, Redux, iQuery, Node, Express, Passport, AWS S3, Bootstrap, Jest, PowerShell

#### **Software:**

Git, Atom, VS Code & Visual Studio, Postman, Jira, DevSuite, Trello, VirtualBox, Docker

## **Experience**

Student Full Stack Web Developer - October 2020 - present Prime Digital Academy

### Solo Project - The General Organizational Tech Tracker (GOTT) - GitHub - Live

GOTT is a lightweight full-stack web application for IT asset management. The application features a full CRUD RESTful API with search and data visualization, as well as multiple authorization levels.

Technologies Used: React, Redux, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, Passport, Chart.js

### Group Client Project - Freehand Cards - GitHub

Freehand Cards is a full-stack web service to assist forgetful gift-givers in getting thoughtful cards for important people in their lives. Responsible for implementing an image upload API, backend admin REST API, protected routes, and user authorization, as well as a scheduled emailer service.

Technologies Used: React, Redux, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, Passport, AWS S3, Nodemailer

# Senior Desktop Support Technician - March 2020 - present

Activision Publishing

- Developed internal website for centralized operational documentation
- Authored new SOP to increase accuracy and scalability of IT operations
- Implemented technical and logistical solutions to minimize pandemic impact on productivity

# Senior Technical Test Analyst • September 2018 – March 2020

Activision Publishing

- Designed high-impact black-box test procedures to enhance issue submission quality
- Spearheaded test build deployment plans and optimizations

### Pre-Calculus, Physics, and Computer Science Tutor • September 2017 – September 2018 Varsity Tutors, Contract

- Created empathetic lesson plans to bolster confidence and retention of technical coursework
- Translated complex concepts to students in clear, easy to understand language

#### Computer Engineering Intern • January 2017 – June 2017 Medtronic

- Converted physical hardware tests to a virtualized test environment
- Collaborated with firmware R&D to debug automated testing software

## **Education**

Full Stack Software Engineering Certification • October 2020 – March 2021

Prime Digital Academy

- Immersed in a 20-week full-stack software engineering program which taught fundamental software engineering concepts such as tech research, collaborative problem solving, and unit testing.
- Trained in professional, team-focused software engineering skills such as the agile methodology and scrum framework, project management, project scope development, and client presentations.

### Computer Engineering Major • 2016 – 2017

University of Minnesota – Twin Cities

- Institute of Electrical & Electronics Engineers (IEEE)
- University Transfer Student Board

#### Engineering Major • 2014 – 2016

Rochester Community and Technical College

- President of the Physics and Engineering Club
- PTK (Phi Theta Kappa) Honors Society Member
- Guest Speaker at AHAC (Academic High-Altitude Conference) 2016 Summer Conference
- Guest Speaker at AAPT (American Association of Physics Teachers) 2016 Winter Conference